To: HR Representative

I have 30+ years in product development and a decade of experience as a CIO / CTO. I have several years of service at the executive level of medium and large companies. I have led teams that have designed and implemented solutions for high-volume financial transaction processing systems, healthcare clinical and revenue cycle management, retail eCommerce / ERP solutions (PCI-DSS Certified) and embedded hardware products. My teams have implemented SaaS solutions on Azure and AWS, using database platforms as diverse as Mongo/Cosmos and Hadoop. For the past seven years my teams have been using automated testing (test-driven development) with continuous integration and deployment for rapid delivery of business value to customers. All systems were dependent on robust Dev Ops systems utilizing GitHub, Jenkins, Team City, Kubernetes and Docker technologies. We abstracted everything by implementing REST API's using MuleSoft for governance.

As a CIO I reduced costs significantly through consolidation, virtualization and cloud migration while improving uptime to greater than 99.9%. I know how to build teams that ensure platforms are secure with efficient networks and elastic capacity at a low cost. I know how to build relationships with customers and clients within and outside of a company.

I have significant startup experience, including an IPO, that I am happy to discuss.

My largest team was 125 people with a budget of \$25 million. Most recently my teams were widely dispersed, including several national locations plus India and Portugal.

Thank you Philip Pointer

Philip Pointer Page 2

PHILIP POINTER

(614) 451-3188 ppointer@gmail.com

CIO/VP Information Technology executive with global experience in high-growth companies, from enterprise to start-ups. Experienced at building and deploying mobile payment and loyalty systems, embedded systems, big data systems, and cloud computing. Specialties are product development and infrastructure management for organizations in financial services, web commerce, retail and healthcare.

EXPERIENCE

Mednax (NYSE:MD), Sunrise, FL, February, 2016 – June, 2019

VP Application Development

Mednax is the nation's largest provider of maternal-fetal, newborn, pediatric, and anesthesia physician services, with \$4B in revenues.

- Leading all of application development for Corporate. Up to 80 FTE and \$7M budget. Teams dispersed internationally
- Delivered remote charge capture, mobile productivity, electronic health records systems, largescale integrations with hospital partners, automation of claims adjustments, revenue cycle management, and business intelligence systems via SaaS model and mobile platforms
- Technology includes Angular, .Net, Mongo/Cosmos, SQL Server, TeamCity, GitHub, Kubernetes, Docker, AWS and Azure with complete CI/CD and automated testing

Velocity targets, budgets, product ROI and client expectations routinely met

Pillar Technology (now Accenture, NASDAQ:ACN), Columbus, OH, January, 2013 - February, 2016

VP Delivery Executive

Leading teams delivering business value at a rapid pace to multiple companies, including a \$5B private label credit card provider and a Fortune 100 \$37B agricultural machinery manufacturer. Team sizes were up to 60 developers. Methodology was agile/scrum, utilizing extreme programming (XP) with automated testing (TDD & BDD), Dev Ops, complete CI/CD

Products delivered included mobile payment and loyalty applications, embedded vehicle systems, big data and cloud computing. Industries were retail, banking, manufacturing, health care and insurance. The technology included C++, Swift, Jenkins, Mercurial, QT, Java, Linux, Hadoop

P&L accountability in this position was ~\$10M annually

IGC, Inc, Columbus, OH, June 2008 – January, 2013

IGC was a private equity firm with interests in several companies. CIO in residence for three of these, including NationsHealth, Inc, a \$100M provider of medical supplies in Columbus, OH, & Sunrise, FL. Accomplishments include:

- Implemented billing system enhancements for claim rejection handling that reduced AR from 150 to 56 days outstanding
- Implemented IVR, cloud and mobility self-service orders, driving 25% of re-orders out of the call center
- Cut data center costs by 50% while doubling system capacity by consolidating servers and implementing enterprise virtualization
- Tripled call center agent seats to 1,100 for Medicare open enrollment using desktop virtualization while maintaining better than 99% uptime. Call centers located in multiple states, with a subsequent rollout to the Philippines
- Implemented a standard M&A procedure that ensured patient acquisitions were implemented within 30 days
- Contributions improved EBITDA from breakeven to \$9M
- Platforms included Win Server, Linux, Ubuntu, and utilized .Net, C#, Java, SQL Server and MySQL. Up to 80 FTE and \$8M budget

Philip Pointer Page 3

DSW, Inc. (NYSE:DSW), Columbus, OH, November, 2006 - April, 2008

Consultant, ERP and eCommerce Implementation for \$2B retailer:

- VP-level position that reported to the CIO. \$4M budget, 12 FTE
- Headed systems architecture team to build 100 CPU hardware platform for ATG (now Oracle EBS), Yantra, GIS, Genesys and Oracle DB; platform sized and certified for 1 million annual order lines and 25k simultaneous customers; project completed on time and within budget
- Defined ERP and Supply Chain Systems architecture for Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) for integration with existing legacy systems and JDA merchandising system
- Linux-based, J2EE Platform was PCI-DSS Level 1 certified and SOX compliant

VenJuvo, dba The Drop Spot, Columbus, OH May, 2005 - November, 2006

CIO for retail service provider. VenJuvo provided trade in/trade up capabilities of consumer electronics to retailers. Key accomplishments:

- Developed business strategy and plans; developed operational procedures and supporting technology
- Managed all product development and rolled out web-based retail B2C tools
- Implemented onsite and offsite infrastructure, ecommerce web site, SEO and web advertising campaigns

Sypherlink, Inc., Dublin, OH August, 2001 - May, 2005

CTO for software and services provider. Key activities:

- Developed business strategy and plans; secured funding totaling \$8M
- Managed all product development, IT functions and client implementations for Sypherlink's automated data integration acceleration product
- Platforms were Windows and Unix, utilizing C++, Ruby, SQL Server, and MySQL
- Listed as Inventor, **US patent** #7039650
- Company was sold to Saama Technologies

SubmitOrder, Inc., Dublin, OH February, 2000 – July, 2001

Senior Director, Software Development for \$40M logistics fulfillment provider. Accomplishments include:

- Implemented CyberSource and PaylinX payments applications
- Implemented Siebel CRM for 250 seat response center, and PkMS for automated distribution facilities with a capacity of 200,000 orders per day
- Developed Order Management and Data Warehouse (OLAP) applications and integrated with Oracle Manufacturing (Commerce) Suite (now EBS)
- Implemented 21 clients, including MLB, American Eagle, Dick's Sporting Goods, Estee Lauder
- Platforms were Sun Unix and IBM AS/400, utilizing Java, J2EE, and Oracle
- 120 FTE located in multiple states and Bangalore, India; \$25M budget

NCS HealthCare, Inc. (now OmniCare, NYSE:OCR), Columbus, OH November, 1996 - April, 1999

Director, Software Development for \$700M prescription drug provider. Key activities:

- Developed on-line pharmacy, care-plan, prescription fulfillment and pre-admissions screening applications
- Implemented automated contract compliance
- Platforms were Unix, C, Citrix, SQL Server and Progress
- Company was sold to OmniCare
- 15 FTE and \$2M budget

Philip Pointer Page 4

CheckFree Corporation, (now Fiserv) (NASDAQ:FISV) Columbus, OH March, 1988 - November, 1996

Senior Staff Software Engineer and **Applications Development Manager** for \$1b financial services provider. Key activities:

- Developed the very first consumer electronic bill payment software system; grew subscriber base from nothing to hundreds of millions of consumers. Systems interacted directly with ACH
- Developed an API, used by Intuit, MECA and CA. Certified Quicken, Managing Your Money and Simply Money for CheckFree bill payment capability
- Implemented IVR capability for bill payment. System was rolled out to several dozen banks
- Implemented Base24-Telebanking software that connected CheckFree to banks' ATM networks; added 140 bank clients in 1996 worth \$40M in revenue
- Platforms included DEC Alpha, IBM ES9600, Tandem, Microsoft and Sun Sparc
- Listed as Inventor, **US patents** #5383113, #5873072, #7107244 and #7240031
- Up to 50 FTE and \$2M budget

CUC International / Affinion, Columbus, OH March, 1984 – March, 1988

Applications Developer. Key activities:

- Developed membership, billing and shopping services
- Platforms included DEC VAX clustered systems and CompuServe DEC 10 & 20. Utilized Fortran, XF4, C, and System 1032 DBMS

EDUCATION

BS, Computer Information Systems, The Ohio State University

CHARITY AFFILIATIONS

Epilepsy Foundation of Central Ohio – former board member Team Greyhound – adoption agency for retired racing greyhounds – volunteer, former board member TAASC – The Adaptive Athletic Sports Coalition – volunteer, former board member